Having felt an earnest call to ministry since college, I have been preparing for both foreign missions and domestic church ministry through internship opportunities, academic study, voracious reading, intense dialog, and a foray into electronic publishing while simultaneously pursuing a career in software development. Although my primary focus has been church health, including church planting and church strengthening, I have also been gifted in personal counseling and have experience in adoption ministry. I hope to transition into vocational ministry upon completion of my M.Div.

I affirm the <u>Abstract of Principles</u>, the <u>Baptist Faith and Message 2000</u>, the <u>Chicago Statement on Biblical Inerrancy</u>, and the <u>Danvers Statement on Biblical Manhood and Womanhood</u>.

Personal Background

Family

Kathryn Rose (spouse), Vernon Ray, IV (11), Brooklyn Leigh (8), Emma Grace (4), Seth Christopher (1).

Some of our children were adopted in 2011.

Contact

81 McDowell Dr.

Wake Forest, North Carolina 27587

vernon.king@outlook.com | (817) 458-8174

Website: http://www.vernonking.org

Sermons: http://www.vernonking.org/sermons/ Family blog: http://www.adoptedbytheking.com



Education

Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary | Wake Forest, North Carolina

Currently pursuing Master of Divinity in Christian Ministry

Anticipated graduation: December 2014

GPA: 4.0

Southwestern Baptist Theological Seminary | Fort Worth, Texas

Coursework toward *Master of Divinity in Missions*

GPA: 4.0+

2009 - 2011

Texas A&M University | College Station, Texas

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

GPA: 4.0, summa cum laude

May 2007

Relevant Experience

First Baptist Church | Durham, North Carolina

Pastoral Intern January 2014 – May 2014

Met weekly with pastors to discuss ministry in a healthy church:

- Attended elders and members meetings
- Read and reported weekly on ecclesiological texts

Pillar on the Rock | Ecclesiological Online Magazine

Co-founder and Editor, www.pillarontherock.com

2009 - 2011

Wrote and edited articles promoting healthy local churches:

- Article reprinted in B&H book, *Preach: Theology Meets Practice*, by Mark Dever and Greg Gilbert
- Edited 100+ articles; Authored 50+ articles (www.pillarontherock.com/search/label/PJ King)
- Wrote major series on divorce and remarriage, race, membership, and church discipline
- Grew the writing team to include six authors

New Song Church | Windhoek, Namibia

Missionary Intern May 2007 – August 2007

Residential intern with an IMB missionary church and youth ministry:

- Assisted in the leadership and administration of a 150+ youth outreach program
- Helped host two American youth mission teams for two weeks each
- Provided technical support for church, youth ministries, and camp

Church Background

First Baptist Church | Durham, North Carolina

Member 2013 – Present

Serving the church in a variety of teaching roles:

- Home Fellowship (small group) co-leader and teacher (Fall 2014)
- Bible for Life teacher, fifth grade boys (Fall 2014)
- Bible for Life teacher, two year-olds (Fall 2013)

Church of Christ the King (SBC) | Fort Worth, Texas

Member 2010 – 2012

Considered faithful to the community and participated in *ad hoc* duties:

- Deacon candidate (moved out of town soon after nomination)
- Organized greeter and security rotations
- Administered web technologies

Portland Avenue Baptist Church | Oklahoma City, Oklahoma Member 2008 – 2009 Sacrificially served while discerning future ministry goals: Interim College and Career Director Break-out teacher for youth ministry Assumed temporary guardianship for twin teenage girls from the youth group Trinity Baptist Church | Norman, Oklahoma Attended Actively participated before planned move out of town.

Engaged in ministry during full tenure of college:

• Served as a youth leader

First Baptist Church | Bryan, Texas

Member

Participated in college discipleship programs

First Baptist Church | Woodway, Texas

Member 1992 – 2003

Raised by my parents to be a faithful member:

- Baptized by Michael Toby, 1992
- Served on student leadership team during high school
- Counseled as a college leader for youth camps and mission trips

Professional History

Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary | Wake Forest, North Carolina Software Developer May 2013 – Present

FTS International | Fort Worth, Texas

Lead Software Developer May 2011 – January 2013

Led a team of five engineers and served as a point of contact with management

Deloitte Consulting | Dallas, Texas

Software Consultant, Homeland Security January 2011 – May 2011

FIS | Oklahoma City, Oklahoma

Senior Programmer Analyst October 2009 – November 2010
Programmer Analyst II September 2007 – October 2009

2003 - 2007

Hewlett-Packard | College Station, Texas

ASIC Intern May 2006 – May 2007

Texas A&M University | College Station, Texas

Peer Teacher, Department of Computer Science

September 2004 – May 2006

References

Nathan Finn, Ph.D.

Elder, First Baptist Church, Durham

Associate Professor, Historical Theology and Baptist Studies, Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary
(919) 280-4309

nfinn@sebts.edu

Benjamin H. Arbour, Ph.D.

Mentor and Friend (979) 574-1300 benarbour03@yahoo.com

Andy Winn, M.Div.

Associate Pastor, First Baptist Church, Durham (919) 452-1427
andy.winn@fbcdurham.org

Ryan Hutchinson, M.Div.

Elder, First Baptist Church, Durham

Executive Vice President for Operations, Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary
(919) 761-2200

hutchinson@sebts.edu

David Jacks

Lead Pastor, Church of Christ the King (817) 395-2180 davidjacks1967@gmail.com